Guide to the Brooklyn Historical Society vertical files ARC.315
Brooklyn Historical Society
Brooklyn Historical Society vertical files
1780-2018
Brooklyn Historical Society
ARC.315
4 Linear Feet in 2 filing cabinet drawers
The Brooklyn Historical Society vertical files is an artificial collection compiled by Brooklyn Historical Society staff. The collection contains pamphlets, cards, advertisements, newspaper articles, magazines, letters, and more dating roughly from 1770 to the present documenting New York City and Long Island. This collection also includes biographical files on notable Brooklyn individuals.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Brooklyn Historical Society vertical files is an artificial collection compiled by Brooklyn Historical Society staff. Exact provenance of the materials in the collection is largely unknown.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into two series:
Series 1. New York City and Long Island
Series 2. Biographical.
Series 1 is arranged alphabetically by subject, while Series 2 is organized alphabetically by surname.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains pamphlets, cards, advertisements, newspaper articles, magazines, letters, and more dating roughly from 1770 to the present.
The first series documents life in New York City and Long Island, including individual communities, organizations, and events. This series includes materials on counties and boroughs such as Queens, Staten Island, and Suffolk County.
The second series documents individuals from Brooklyn and Brooklyn-based families. Notable individuals represented in this collection include Walt Whitman, Henry Ward Beecher, Gabriel Furman, Jackie Robinson, and members of the Roebling and Shellens families. This collection also includes information about lesser known organizations and individuals.
African Americans; Baseball -- New York (State) -- New York; Historic preservation -- New York (State) -- New York; Museums -- New York (State) -- New York; Parks -- New York (State) -- New York; Public Schools -- New York (State) -- New York; Charities -- New York (State) -- New York; Political clubs -- New York (State) -- New York; Staten Island (New York, N.Y.); Gay culture -- New York (State) -- New York; Manhattan (New York, N.Y.); Long Island (N.Y.); Long Island (N.Y.) -- History; Queens County (N.Y.); Queens County (N.Y.) -- History; Bronx (New York, N.Y.); Suffolk County (N.Y.); Suffolk County (N.Y.) -- History; Newsletters; Chinatown (New York, N.Y.); Nassau County (N.Y.)
- Series 1: New York City and Long Island, circa 1850-2018; 2 Linear Feet in 1 filing cabinet drawer
  - African Americans (Drawer 1)
  - Art and Artists (Drawer 1)
  - Baseball (Drawer 1)
  - Bridges (Drawer 1)
  - Bronx (Drawer 1)
  - Buildings (Drawer 1)
  - Business and Businesses -- General (Drawer 1)
  - Business and Businesses -- Long Island Lighting Company (LILCO) (Drawer 1)
  - Cemeteries (Drawer 1)
  - Churches (Drawer 1)
  - Clubs (Drawer 1)
  - Disasters (Drawer 1)
  - Entertainment (Drawer 1)
  - Environment -- General (Drawer 1)
  - Environment -- Long Island Sound Studies (Drawer 1)
  - Health (Drawer 1)
  - Historic Preservation -- Brownstone Revival Committee (Drawer 1)
  - Historic Preservation -- Friends of Cast Iron Architecture (Drawer 1)
  - Historic Preservation -- Historic House Trust (Drawer 1)
  - Historic Preservation -- Landmarks (Drawer 1)
  - Historic Preservation -- National Trust for Historic Preservation (Drawer 1)
  - Historic Preservation -- Preservation League of New York State (Drawer 1)
  - Historic Preservation -- Society for the Preservation of Long Island (Drawer 1)
  - History (Drawer 1)
  - Housing (Drawer 1)
  - Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender and Queer (LGBTQ) (Drawer 1)
  - Libraries (Drawer 1)
  - Long Island -- Amityville (Drawer 1)
  - Long Island -- Babylon (Drawer 1)
  - Long Island -- Dix Hills (Drawer 1)
  - Long Island -- East Hampton (Drawer 1)
  - Long Island -- Island Review magazine (Drawer 1)
  - Long Island -- Nassau County (Drawer 1)
  - Long Island -- Old Beth Page (Drawer 1)
  - Long Island -- Oyster Bay (Drawer 1)
  - Long Island -- Port Jefferson (Drawer 1)
  - Long Island -- Queens Village (Drawer 1)
  - Long Island -- Roslyn (Drawer 1)
  - Long Island -- Sag Harbor (Drawer 1)
  - Long Island -- Shelter Island (Drawer 1)
  - Long Island -- Southampton (Drawer 1)
  - Long Island -- Stony Brook (Drawer 1)
  - Long Island -- Suffolk County (Drawer 1)
  - Maritime (Drawer 1)
  - Military (Drawer 1)
  - Monuments and Statues (Drawer 1)
  - Museums -- General (Drawer 1)
  - Museums -- American Museum of Natural History (Drawer 1)
  - Museums -- Castle Clinton National Monument (Drawer 1)
  - Museums -- Metropolitan Museum of Art (Drawer 1)
  - Museums -- Museum of the City of New York (Drawer 1)
  - Museums -- New York Historical (Drawer 1)
  - Museums -- Nassau County Museums (Drawer 1)
  - Museums -- Queens Historical Society (Drawer 1)
  - Museums -- Queens Museum (Drawer 1)
  - Museums -- Sleepy Hollow Restoration (Drawer 1)
  - Museums -- South Street Seaport Museum (Drawer 1)
  - Museums -- Studio Museum in Harlem (Drawer 1)
  - Museums -- Suffolk County Marine Museum (Drawer 1)
  - Museums -- University Art Gallery of the University State (Drawer 1)
  - Museums -- Whaling Museum, Cold Spring Harbor, L..I. (Drawer 1)
  - New Jersey (Drawer 1)
  - New York City (Drawer 1)
  - New York City -- Community News newsletter (Drawer 1)
  - Organizations -- General (Drawer 1)
  - Organizations -- Center for Social Inclusion (Drawer 1)
  - Organizations -- League of Women Voters (Drawer 1)
  - Organizations -- Long Island Association (Drawer 1)
  - Organizations -- New York State Coalition of Concerned Legal Professionals (Drawer 1)
  - Organizations -- Queens Botanical Garden Society (Drawer 2)
  - Parks -- General (Drawer 2)
  - Parks -- Battery Park and Battery Park Basin (Drawer 2)
  - Parks -- Central Park (Drawer 2)
  - Parks -- Flushing Meadow Park (Drawer 2)
  - Parks -- Gateway National Recreation Area (Drawer 2)
  - Parks -- Rochdale Village Park (Drawer 2)
  - Politics, Government, Legal -- Voter Guides (Drawer 2)
  - Politics, Government, Legal -- New York State Supreme Court (Drawer 2)
  - Queens (Drawer 2)
  - Sciences (Drawer 2)
  - Schools (Drawer 2)
  - Schools -- Columbia University (Drawer 2)
  - Social welfare (Drawer 2)
  - Tourism and city guides (Drawer 2)
  - Tourism and state guides (Drawer 2)
  - Transit (Drawer 2)
  - World's Fair 1939 (Drawer 2)
  - World's Fair 1964 (Drawer 2)
- Series 2: Biographical, circa 1780-1990; 2 Linear Feet in 1 filing cabinet drawer
  - Aldridge, Walter Hull (-1959), 1889-1959 (Drawer 10)
  - Andersen, Albert, F.M. (-1961) (Drawer 10)
  - Baker, Bertram (1888/9-1985) (Drawer 10)
  - Barber, Red (1908-), 1988 (Drawer 10)
  - Bard, James (1815-1897), undated (Drawer 10)
  - Bard, John (1815-1856), 1845-1990 (Drawer 10)
  - Barnes, Djuna, 1995 (Drawer 10)
  - Barr, Amelia Edith H., 1911 (Drawer 10)
  - Barrett, William S., 1971-1979 (Drawer 10)
  - Barstowe, Edward, A. (1842- ), 1989 (Drawer 10)
  - Beecher Family, 1860-1906 (Drawer 10)
  - Bennett, Gertrude Ryder, circa 1930s-1970s (Drawer 10)
  - Bjarkman, Peter C. (1941-), 1997 (Drawer 10)
  - Bow, Clara (1905-1965), 1991 (Drawer 10)
  - Brath, Peter (1901-1989) (Drawer 10)
  - Brevoort family (Drawer 10)
  - Byrd, Frederick (1805-1857), 1995 (Drawer 10)
  - Cadman, S(amuel) Parkes, 1926 (Drawer 10)
  - Chisholm, Shirley (1924-2005), undated (Drawer 10)
  - Colson family, 2018 (Drawer 10)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Written and researched by and gift of Colson descendant Rev. Barbara Ann Porceddu.
  - Cooper, John Walcott (1873-1966), 1982 (Drawer 10)
  - Couney, Martin A. (1860/1870-1950), 1939-1979 (Drawer 10)
  - Crane, Nathalia (1913- ), 1936 (Drawer 10)
  - Culin, Stewart (1853-1929), 1989-1990 (Drawer 10)
  - Dillard, Maud Esther, 1924-1977 (Drawer 10)
  - Dykman, Jackson Annan (1887-1974) (Drawer 10)
  - Fabry, Alois (Jr.) (1912-1986), 2006 (Drawer 10)
  - Falconer, John M., 1881-1975 (Drawer 10)
  - Fedde, Elisabeth (Sister) (1850-1921), undated (Drawer 10)
  - Fehrer, Oscar (1872-1958), undated (Drawer 10)
  - Felt, David (1793- ), 1989 (Drawer 10)
  - Ferguson, Max (1959- ), 1990 (Drawer 10)
  - Fisher, Ken, 1991 (Drawer 10)
  - Ford, Gordon Lester (1823-1891), 1970 (Drawer 10)
  - Francis, Virginia Fuller, undated (Drawer 10)
  - Freeman, Frank (1861-1949), 1995 (Drawer 10)
  - Furman, Charles, 1899-1953 (Drawer 10)
  - Furman, Gabriel (1800-1854), 1978 (Drawer 10)
  - Gleason, Jackie (1916-1987) (Drawer 10)
  - Green, Anna Katherine (1846- ), undated (Drawer 10)
  - Green, Roger L., 1989-1992 (Drawer 10)
  - Green, William B., 1893-1894 (Drawer 10)
  - Harrigan, Edward (Ned) (1844-1911), 1980 (Drawer 10)
  - Higgins, Charles Michael, 1977-1978 (Drawer 10)
  - Hofmann, John Gerard "Jerry" (1916-1945) (Drawer 10)
  - Homes, J. Wheldon, 1996 (Drawer 10)
  - Hynes, Charles J. (1935- ), 1980-1996 (Drawer 10)
  - Jolson, Al, undated (Drawer 10)
  - Jordan, MacNeil, undated (Drawer 10)
  - Kelly, James A. (1885-1972), 1944-1977 (Drawer 10)
  - Kroll, Ernest, 1990 (Drawer 10)
  - Lachman, Seymour (1933- ), 1996 (Drawer 10)
  - Lichtenstein, Harvey (1929- ), 1993 (Drawer 10)
  - Lifshey, Samuel H. ( -1954), 1911-1954 (Drawer 10)
  - Loomis, Harvey Worthington (1865-1930), 1930-1990 (Drawer 10)
  - Low, Seth (Drawer 10)
  - Madden, John B, (1919-1988) (Drawer 10)
  - Manbeck, John B, 1993 (Drawer 10)
  - Marlor, Clark S. (1922- ), 1993 (Drawer 10)
  - Matthews, William (1822-1896), 1892-1896 (Drawer 10)
  - Maynard, Joan (d.2006), 1979 (Drawer 10)
  - McLean, Samuel, undated (Drawer 10)
  - Meadows, Audrey ( -1966), 1996 (Drawer 10)
  - Melish, John Howard ( -1969), 1969-1990 (Drawer 10)
  - Metz, Bill, 1940 (Drawer 10)
  - Montgomery, Velmanette, 1989-1992 (Drawer 10)
  - Moore, Mary Tyler (1936- ), 1996 (Drawer 10)
  - Morris, Montrose W. (1861-1916) (Drawer 10)
  - Moses, Robert [3 folders], 1975-1976 (Drawer 10)
  - Munson, Audrey, 1913-1920 (Drawer 10)
  - Murphy, Henry Cruse (1810--1882), 1986 (Drawer 10)
  - Nissen, Ludwig (1855-1924), undated (Drawer 10)
  - Ockley, Victor (1943-1988), 1987-1988 (Drawer 10)
  - Othmer, Donald F. (1904-1995), 1978-1995 (Drawer 10)
  - Owens, Major (1936- ), 1991 (Drawer 10)
  - Pantano, Nino, 1974-1977 (Drawer 10)
  - Papp, Joseph (1921-1991) (Drawer 10)
  - Parker, Edgard Rudolph (1872-1952), 1986 (Drawer 10)
  - Patterson, David J., undated (Drawer 10)
  - Paull, Edward T. ( -1924), 1988 (Drawer 10)
  - Peace, Harvey W. (1830-1907), 1993 (Drawer 10)
  - Pennell, Joseph (1857-1926) (Drawer 10)
  - Perkins, Rebecca Talbot (1866-1956), 2009 (Drawer 10)
  - Pinkett, Mary, 1989-1992 (Drawer 10)
  - Pope, Abbie Hanscom, 1984 (Drawer 10)
  - Ransom, Theodore Sedgwick, 1864-1881 (Drawer 10)
  - Read, Helen Appleton, 1967-1973 (Drawer 10)
  - Reed, Tucker (Drawer 10)
  - Reynolds, William H., 1931-1994 (Drawer 10)
  - Robinson, Jackie (1919-1972), 1997 (Drawer 10)
  - Roebling, Emily Warren, 1983-1996 (Drawer 10)
  - Roebling, Washington Augustus, 1988-1994 (Drawer 10)
  - Rosten, Norman (1914-1995), 1979-1995 (Drawer 10)
  - Ryan, Jom, 1990 (Drawer 10)
  - Sanford, Joseph (1797-1831), 1872-1972 (Drawer 10)
  - Schilders, Ed, 1980 (Drawer 10)
    Biographical note
    Dutch publisher of Brooklyn Bridge Bulletin magazine.
  - Schlech, Walter F. (1915- ), 1924-1969 (Drawer 10)
  - Schneerson, Menachem, 1992 (Drawer 10)
  - Secor, John Alstyne, 1980 (Drawer 10)
  - See, Alonzo Bertram (1848-1941), 1995 (Drawer 10)
  - Seidl, Anton (1850-1898), 1991 (Drawer 10)
  - Selby, Hubert (Jr.) (1928- ), 1990 (Drawer 10)
  - Shellens, Michael (1854-1944), 2006 (Drawer 10)
  - Shellens, Ruth M. (1905-1988), 1987-1988 (Drawer 10)
  - Sito, Tom, 1988 (Drawer 10)
  - Sliwa, Curtis, 1970-1980 (Drawer 10)
  - Sliwa, Fran, 1988 (Drawer 10)
  - Smith, Betty (1896-1972) (Drawer 10)
  - Smith, Cyrus Porter ( -1877), 1932 (Drawer 10)
  - Soligny, Eugene Julius, 1990 (Drawer 10)
  - Somers, Arthur S. (Drawer 10)
  - Srebnik, Craig, undated (Drawer 10)
  - Steward, Susan Smith McKinney (1847- ), 1983 (Drawer 10)
  - Stillman, Thomas E. (1826-1906) (Drawer 10)
  - Storrs, Richard Salter, 1880-1896 (Drawer 10)
  - Stryker-Rodda, Kenn (1903-1990) (Drawer 10)
  - Tanzman, Roslyn, 1994 (Drawer 10)
  - Toedteberg, Emma (1824-1909), 1936 (Drawer 10)
  - Towns, Edolphus (1934- ), 1988 (Drawer 10)
  - Trask, Katrina (1853-1922) (Drawer 10)
  - Turnbull, Charles, 1780-1791 (Drawer 10)
  - Van Brunt, James Ryder (1820-1916), 1845-1965 (Drawer 10)
  - Vaux, Calvert (1824-1895), undated (Drawer 10)
  - Vincent, Paul, 1975 (Drawer 10)
  - Volkmar, Charles, 1900 (Drawer 10)
  - Wengenroth, Stow (1906-1978), undated (Drawer 10)
  - White, Alfred T. (1846-1921), 1989-1993 (Drawer 10)
  - Whitman, Walt (1819-1892), 1846-1995 (Drawer 10)
  - Willensky, Elliot ( -1990) (Drawer 10)
  - Woodhull, Nathaniel (1722-1776), undated (Drawer 10)